<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World ! on Ajmal Bin Nizam</title>
    <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello World ! on Ajmal Bin Nizam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal website</title>
      <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>i&amp;rsquo;m from an non cs background and i thought it would be hard to make website but crossroads really breaked all my myth it was actually pretty easy to make a responive simple website.
  I learned a lot about html css bootstrap and javascript,from web desiging challenge from crossroads youtube channel,
  But with julio codes youtube tutorial i started to make a website of my dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CORONAGO Game</title>
      <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>I was so bored during quarentine and think about my childhood dreams and one was making my own game. I learnt a lot of python through many tutorials and completed two nptel courses and i was looking forward to do a project and the pygame concept shook me. I just modified simple space invader to my own styled corona game using freecodecamp youtube video  checkout my instagram for more info 😍</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science salary estimator</title>
      <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that estimates data science salaries to help data scientists negotiate their income when they get a job. Scraped over 1000 job descriptions from glassdoor using python and selenium Engineered features from the text of each job description to quantify the value companies put on python, excel, aws, and spark. Optimized Linear, Lasso, and Random Forest Regressors using GridsearchCV to reach the best model. Built a client facing API using flask        Link to github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Absenteeism</title>
      <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This was my first poject in data sciene it took me approx about two month to complete this udemy course, but it was worth the time i studied my important facts and shortcut to quickly understand the data science whole working part.
Currently, organizations are seeking to find the main causes behind absence. This subject has been studied before decades form a different perspective.
THE MAIN OBJECTIVE IS TO FIND 120 EMPLOYEES ABSENTEEISM FACTORS BASED ON DATA ANALYSIS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajmalbinnizam.github.io/ajuprojects/contact/</guid>
      <description>Please feel free to contact me, it&amp;rsquo;s always free and open, i will reach you ASAP 😉
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>